Louys, Pierre, 1870-1925. Papers (MS Fr 233): Guide.
Papers,
1890-1919 and undated.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Fr 233
Louys, Pierre, 1870-1925.
1 v. (.1 linear ft.)
Letters and compositions of French writer Pierre Louys.
*64M-131
Purchased with the Amy Lowell fund; received: 1965 Jan 10.
Pierre Louys was a French writer of the Parnassian school
Organized into the following series:
I. Letters
II. Compositions
Contains letters by Pierre Louys, chiefly to Georges Louys, and compositions, including autograph manuscripts containing a draft of a poem, table of contents of a projected anthology of French verse, a book review, and essay on the French orator Jacques Bénigne Bossuet.
- I. Letters
  - Louys, Pierre, 1870-1925. 9 A.L.s. to Georges Louys:
    - [n.p., Oct 1894]., (1); 1s.(2p.)
    - Rue de Sully, 30 Jan [1902]., (2); 1s.(4p.)
    - Biarritz, 14 Mar [1903]., (3); 1s.(3p.) env.
    - [n.p., 29 Mar 1905]., (4); 3s.(7p.) env.
      Includes A.L.s. from François Charles Roux to Pierre Louys; 21 Mar 1905.
    - [n.p.] 7 Oct [1914]., (5); 1s.(4p.)
    - [n.p.] 8 Oct [1914]., (6); 1s.(3p.)
    - [n.p.] 9 Oct [1914]., (7); 1s.(4p.)
    - [n.p., 23 Nov 1914]., (8); 1s.(2p.)
    - [n.p., n.d.]., (9); 1s.(3p.)
  - Louys, Pierre, 1870-1925. 10 A.L. to Paul Souday; [Paris, 1919]., (10-19)
    Mostly unfinished drafts of one letter.
  - Louys, Pierre, 1870-1925. 6 A.L. to unidentified persons; [1915-1919 n.d.], (20-25)
  - Louys, Georges. A.L. to [Pierre Louys]; [n.p., n.d.]., (26); 3s.(3p.)
    Includes A.MS. notes and draft of a poem by Pierre Louys.
- II. Compositions
  - Anthologie. A.MS.; [n.p.] Jan-Jul 1890., (27); 37s.(43p.)
    Table of contents of a projected anthology of French verse.
  - Antiperistase on contraires differences d'amour. A.MS.; [n.p., n.d.]., (28); 21s.(21p.)
    Book review.
  - [Book lists] A.MS.; [n.p., n.d.]., (29); 5s.(7p.)
  - [Essay on Bossuet] A.MS. (fragment); [n.p., n.d.]., (30); 4s.(11p.)
  - Mots inconnus. A.MS.; [n.p.] Nov 1891., (31); 6f.(11p.)
    Beginning of a dictionary of unusual words; "abaca" to "alucite".
  - Miscellaneous notes and translations. A.MS.; [n.p., n.d.]., (32); 6s.(10p.)
  - clippings., (33)